POONAM PATEL

GIS Specialist

Email: pvp.poonam@gmail.com Mobile: +65-87532218

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/poonam-patel-gis-specialist/

Portfolio: https://poonamvpatel.github.io/

SUMMARY

GIS Specialist, having a Master's in Geomatics with 5+ years of experience enables me to meet the diverse requirements of the converging industry. I am currently seeking a challenging opportunity through which I can grow my knowledge and implement my learnt skills, thus effectively contributing to the company. An eye for detail, creative thinking and delivering results efficiently are qualities I bring with me.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer 2021-present

Responsible for developing outputs using GIS as per Clients needs and requirements.

Singapore Land Authority, Singapore

11/2019 -11/2020

Senior Geospatial Specialist

- · Responsible for creating and maintaining spatial and attribute data, Processing the GIS data for OneMap routing
- Responsible for creation of PL/SQL scripts (cycling, Driving, Walking) to process data for routing
- Web application development and design using HTML / JavaScript / Leaflet/OpenLayers /Node.js /PostgreSQL
- Create raster tiles and vector tiles for base map using GIS data.
- Perform research to obtain and expand existing datasets and technologies.
- Gather and report on GIS data and determine how data sets are best utilized through GIS.

Quantum Inventions, Singapore

03/2019 -07/2019

Intern-GIS Developer

• Responsible for developing pedestrian routing for Singapore using Django-Python, Postgres, Leaflet

ENVIRONMENTAL MANAGEMENT CENTRE LLP, Mumbai, India

01/2017 -06/2018

GIS Specialist

- Responsible for developing the GIS outputs for projects such as Geodatabase creation, Conducting LULC Classification and Watershed Analysis, Geo-referencing of the satellite images, satellite image processing, mosaicking and toposheets.
- Supported project workflows, data preparation, data storage, GIS modeling and analysis, development of technical, professional project reports
- Create maps and graphs, using GIS software and data collection equipment.
- Generation of base shape files through digitization, Database creation, Production of various thematic maps for reports and presentation, Generations of Reports.
- Performing Shadow Flicker and Noise Modelling Formulating impact scenarios. Spatiotemporal analysis and creating modelling outputs for various themes of the project.

MAHATMA EDUCATION SOCIETY- UXO, Navi Mumbai, India

06/2015 -09/2016

Image Analyst

Responsible for measuring the quality of expansion in urban areas using high resolution imagery.

- Measurement of the quality of urban expansion, Satellite Image processing, Spatiotemporal analysis, Land Use categorization, Arterial Road mapping using Satellite data and other sources.
- · Designs, creates, updates, and maintains geographic data and maps
- Data quality assessment on raster and vector data formats.

CEPT University, Ahmedabad, India

01/2015 - 05/2015

Teaching Associate

- Developed course work Structure for subject GIS for landscape architecture.
- Delivered practical sessions and hands on training on GIS and Reviewed students work and assignments.

National Institute of Rural Development, Hyderabad, India

06/2014 - 07/2014

Intern

• Developed land use land cover mapping, change detection using satellite data.

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore, Singapore

08/2018 -07/2019

Graduate Diploma in Systems Analysis

Relevant Coursework: Application Development Life Cycle, Project Management, java script, Python, HTML, CSS

CEPT University, Ahmedabad, India

2013 - 2015

Master of Science in Geomatics

- Master's thesis on Vulnerability Index Modeling sponsored by ISRO. The main objective of the study is to develop automated tool in ArcGIS using model builder.
- Some other academic projects included, Ward planning, analysis for TOZ area, Tool for Site Suitability Analysis, Designing Route Map for —Bike Racing Routes, Change detection etc.

Indian Institute of Remote Sensing, Dehradun, India

08/2014 - 03/2015

Remote sensing & GIS for Natural Resources Remote Sensing, GIS & Global Navigation Satellite System

- Relevant Coursework: Remote Sensing, Forest mapping & density assessment using RS data using visual & digital techniques
- · Relevant Coursework: Basics of Remote Sensing, GIS and GNSS, Digital Image Analysis, Digital Image Processing

M.G Science Institute, Ahmedabad, India

2010 - 2013

Bachelor in Geology

• Relevant Coursework: Concepts of Geologic materials, Structural geology, Petrology and Applied geology.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Geomatics ArcGIS, Q GIS, ERDAS IMAGINE, JOSM, Envi, Google Earth, PostgreSQL

Programming HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, OpenLayers, Leaflet, NodeJS

Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Project

OTHER INTERESTS

I am a keen artist, regularly painting (glass) to a high standard to relax. I further regularly participate in a variety of cultural events, organizing and volunteering at numerous events.